my name is jim hindu and today I'll be talking about how you can discover devices
are services on your local network using your windows ten device.
We'll be taking a look at what is the...and what it takes to create
nap using the dns as the api also be providing some resources
at the end so you can create an app on your own and provide feedback to us?
The iness...works hand-in-hand with md
and which is a multi-cast protocol that prevents the need for unicast
server by letting devices communicate with each other directly?
Let's go ahead and take a look at what it takes to build an end-to-end dns as
...app when creating a dns
...up the first thing you need to do is to register yourself by registering
your app other apps will be able to discovery you on the local network.
When registering the app you need to provide a service name which is broken down
into three individual parameters the instance name
is what the apple show when you put it up on the app store is a human readable name
if you're making a simple chat application over the local network we can give it an instance name
such as simple chat app...service-type is what your apps protocol
name is this is what other apps will be searching for when they try to look
your app up on the local network, for example, if you're trying to discover printers using the
iness as the their service-type is dot ip?
For the chat app
...creating we can give it a service-type of sca dot underscore tcp
which means we'll be looking for that app or the tcp protocol.
Domain name is standard dns domain such as microsoft-dot-com on the
local network you can simply use the keyword dot local.
...up you can also specified text attributes that other apps can parse
these are things that might be important to other apps or instances of your own app,
for example,
if you're building a simple chat application other apps may want to know what is the maximum number of
content users that the app can handle you may also want to specify the locale,
for example, english us the next thing the next important thing for building your
app is discovery and resolution this is how other
apps will discover and get information to be able to connect your app.
To do a discovery all the app has to do is do
a search query on the service-type buffer up in this case we look for services of
the type sca or the tcp protocol in this example
we see that are api has discovered two instances of the sca
up on the local network once we have the instance names we can resolve them to
get more important information such as the ip address and the port number
...also get the text attributes that we put in during registration time once we
have the ip address and port number we can use a number of resources to connect to the
other app instance the most common one being the martin sockets api.
Now that we have covered how to create
...sd app let's go ahead and take a look at some code once we have registered
...application will be using the windows
...devices that enumeration api to discover instances of it.
The windows dot devices done enumeration api requires unique
...for each discovery type...looking for...dns
st are bluetooth the unique do it for dns st shown on-screen.
Next up will create a query string for all apps using
...protocol along with their service-type once we have created the
query string we can add a call back to the watcher and started.
Once we have discovered instances a for application on the local network
will retrieve information...us to connect to those instances.
Will be retrieving information such as the ip
address the port number and optional text attributes using the ip address
and the port number we can go ahead and create the socket connection once we have the ip address
and the port number we can go ahead and start to socket connection I don't have a demo
for-you today but please take a look at...st documentation and sample up?
I hope you had fun learning about the
dns st api please take a look at the msdn documentation and
the sample app thank you for watching and I hope you'll be creating your very own...app.